<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intro on Michael Zhang</title>
    <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intro on Michael Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 22:55:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelzhang.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Correct-N-Contrast: a Contrastive Approach for Improving Robustness to Spurious Correlations</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/005-correct_n_contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 12:23:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/005-correct_n_contrast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Federated Learning with First Order Model Optimization</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/004-fedfomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:02:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/004-fedfomo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Computer Vision to Automate Hand Detection and Tracking of Surgeon Movements in Videos of Open Surgery</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/003-surgery_hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 17:41:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/003-surgery_hands/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is fine</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/017-this_is_fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 20:15:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/017-this_is_fine/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Policy Divergence for Personalized Meta-Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/002-policy_divergence_personalized_meta-rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 17:41:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/002-policy_divergence_personalized_meta-rl/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a GitHub Contributions Graph for Life</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/016-making_life_contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 16:25:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/016-making_life_contributions/</guid>
      <description>Something I&amp;rsquo;ve recently realized is that my work habits tend to obey inertia frustratingly well. What I mean is that if I&amp;rsquo;m currently getting a lot done, or coming off a track record of getting things done, I tend to stay focused and continue to get work done. Which is nice. But this also means that if I&amp;rsquo;m being a YouTube-watching potato, I tend to stay a potato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On University Identity Jargon</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/015-college_id_jargon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 15:33:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/015-college_id_jargon/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Hi I&amp;rsquo;m Michael, a third year student&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip;at the college.&amp;rdquo;
I don&amp;rsquo;t always introduce myself like that, but when I do, it&amp;rsquo;s usually in the context of meeting someone new in school, but not necessarily in college. One of the great things about where I go to school is the relative ease in taking grad-level classes1 as an undergrad (doing well in them is another matter). Additionally, certain opportunities and professors seem to be especially keen with working with undergrads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Machine Translation and Sequence-to-Sequence Models</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/010-nmt_seq2seq-tut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 14:44:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/010-nmt_seq2seq-tut/</guid>
      <description>What follows are personal notes and any possible insights to help me understand neural machine translation especially in the context of seq2seq models. All content credit goes to Graham Neubig and his tutorial Neural Machine Translation and Sequence-to-sequence Models: A Tutorial These were done as review for CS 287r.
n-gram Language Models The main issue with these is not being able to capture all possible sentence inputs? We can create a simple maximum likelihood estimator by calculating the probabilities for each word $e_t | e_{t-1}$, but this is only as strong as if we see these in previous training data examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on NamedTensor</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/009-namedtensor_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 16:55:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/009-namedtensor_notes/</guid>
      <description>NamedTensor is a PyTorch library that tries to fix some broken parts of Tensor. As part of CS 287R this year, our class gets to be beta-testing guinea pigs for it.\
While I haven&amp;rsquo;t really worked extensively in PyTorch before, in this post (perhaps the first of many) I&amp;rsquo;ll try to document notes on Tensors and NamedTensor alternatives. Sources will mainly be the NamedTensor blog post written by Sasha Rush&amp;rsquo;s group, and the official PyTorch documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CNNs for NLP</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/008-nlp_cnns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 17:25:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/008-nlp_cnns/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always believed that a better way to learn things is to explain them to others. It&amp;rsquo;s part of why I teach in college. When I started thinking about the merits of a blog, writing about more technical things as a way to ground concepts for myself was definitely a plus. \
This semester, I&amp;rsquo;m taking CS 287R, a class at Harvard that deals with NLP and increasingly deep learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Tokyo Metro Markov Models</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006.1-tokyo_metro_markov-tech_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 23:57:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006.1-tokyo_metro_markov-tech_post/</guid>
      <description>As a follow-up to an earlier post on the real-world experiences / beginning inspiration behind this project (tldr; I was in Japan for three days and it was a lot of fun), I wanted to spend some time documenting how I went about putting together the visualization.
From the start, there was going to be some backend work and some frontend stuff. Because I wanted to build an app that could run purely client-side, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in Japan with Reflections and a Side Project</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006-tokyo_metro_markov_chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 23:18:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006-tokyo_metro_markov_chains/</guid>
      <description>Winter break&amp;rsquo;s been a long one. By now I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to being out of school, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to think that four weeks ago I was in Japan. Family&amp;rsquo;s been on a traveling kick lately, and this year we spent ten days between Tokyo, Kamakura, Hakone, Shanghai, and Beijing.
Although I&amp;rsquo;d been to Tokyo for some epsilon-long layovers before, and this time our time in Japan could probably still only be considered a layover (3 out of 10 days woo), I&amp;rsquo;d still consider the recent trip to be the first time I really got to see the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo Metro Markov Models</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/006-tokyo_metro_markov_chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 22:40:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/006-tokyo_metro_markov_chains/</guid>
      <description>Two things I think are pretty cool: the Tokyo subway system and Markov chains. In all seriousness, as a big proponent of learning by doing, I&amp;rsquo;m always trying to figure out how to combine some theory with real-world application, motivated by creating something cool in the process. Coming home from two weeks in Tokyo + Shanghai and a week in the Bay Area at Hack Lodge, it was a fun way to combine some things I knew about for some time (making maps, markov chains), with things I recently learned about (the Tokyo metro, the &amp;ldquo;joys&amp;rdquo; of React and front-end), and a tiny relation to a preview of stuff yet to come (Stat 212 fun&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction Markets for Multi-Agent Multi-Armed Bandits</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/005-mama_bandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 13:43:56 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/005-mama_bandits/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Things</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/001-starting_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 02:07:49 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/001-starting_things/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s 2:08am on Christmas day in Hakone, Japan as I try to think of a good way to start this1. One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling myself for the last three years is that someday I&amp;rsquo;ll maintain a website that&amp;rsquo;s more than just a cryptic online resume. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;d be a data science blog, something along the lines of FiveThirtyEight or IQuantNY. Or maybe an online repository of side projects and ideas, the prospect of putting them up for someone else to discover supposedly motivating me to finish them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping out SummerCamp NYC 2018</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 22:43:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</guid>
      <description>Second part of a two-part series introducing SummerCamp NYC 2018. Also published on Medium here.
Part 2: Location, Location, &amp;hellip; Intern Preferences! If the students make up the heart of SummerCamp, the events bring them together and keep the community running. While ranging in size and nature, none of them would be possible without the fantastic hosts and partner companies we’ve been able to work with over the years, and a big part of organizing SummerCamp involves coordinating and planning for a series of meet-ups over the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping out SummerCamp NYC 2018</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:29:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</guid>
      <description>Second part of a two-part series introducing SummerCamp NYC 2018. Also published on Medium here.
Part 2: Location, Location, &amp;hellip; Intern Preferences! If the students make up the heart of SummerCamp, the events bring them together and keep the community running. While ranging in size and nature, none of them would be possible without the fantastic hosts and partner companies we’ve been able to work with over the years, and a big part of organizing SummerCamp involves coordinating and planning for a series of meet-ups over the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to SummerCamp NYC 2018</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-intro-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 22:43:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-intro-2018/</guid>
      <description>Part of a two-part series introducing SummerCamp NYC 2018. Also published on Medium here.
Part 1: Meeting the Group of 2018 SummerCamp is a community of Harvard interns in the Bay Area, NYC, Seattle, and now Boston who come together every year to celebrate innovation and technology, focusing on the students and companies at the heart of it all. Through professional and social events, the group aims to connect students with each other, their alums, and leading technology-related companies in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Kinases and Viral Drug Connectivity</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/003-kinase-virus_analysis-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 03:38:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/003-kinase-virus_analysis-post/</guid>
      <description>Source: Maillard Lab
Kinases are pretty interesting to me. Sure I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the best introduction with them - as with most proteins, they were portrayed in AP Biology as either overly simple cartoon squiggly shapes or hopelessly complex ribbon / space-filling models, playing some large role in cell signaling with an equally large number of chemicals and sub-products to memorize. But over time I was able to see past these offenses to arrive at my current sentiment: kinases are kind of cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Assembly of CRISPR/Cas9-based Virus-like Particles for Programmable and Orthogonal Genetic Engineering in Mammalian Cells</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/001-crispr_vlps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 17:40:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/research/001-crispr_vlps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Engineering with CRISPR-Cas9 Virus-like Particles</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/002-crispr_vlps-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 01:37:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/002-crispr_vlps-post/</guid>
      <description>See the paper, poster, and research plan 
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if anyone will ever happen to be on this site looking for resources regarding science fairs, and I definitely don&amp;rsquo;t do as much wet-lab biology as I used to, but as an homage to a past high school obsession passion I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to try to remember some past work.
Some Abstract For some introduction, CRISPR-Cas9 is an exciting gene editing technology with many hyped applications in science and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Engineering with CRISPR-Cas9 Virus-like Particles</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/002-crispr_vlps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 01:37:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/002-crispr_vlps/</guid>
      <description>See the paper, poster, and research plan 
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if anyone will ever happen to be on this site looking for resources regarding science fairs, and I definitely don&amp;rsquo;t do as much wet-lab biology as I used to, but as an homage to a past high school obsession passion I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to try to remember some past work.
Some Abstract For some introduction, CRISPR-Cas9 is an exciting gene editing technology with many hyped applications in science and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbine Optimization Problem</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/001-turbine_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 15:29:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/projects/001-turbine_optimization/</guid>
      <description>Multivariable calculus was a fun time, and for a class project we were tasked with solving a Lagrange optimization problem. This was around the time I started learning about GitHub Pages and hosting websites for various club and activity-related things, so in my youthful enthusiasm I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be cool to turn in a website for the assignment.
Unfortunately for some reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t include the original questions, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of limited there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>