<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualization on Michael Zhang</title>
    <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/tags/data-visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Visualization on Michael Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 23:57:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelzhang.xyz/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Tokyo Metro Markov Models</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006.1-tokyo_metro_markov-tech_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 23:57:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006.1-tokyo_metro_markov-tech_post/</guid>
      <description>As a follow-up to an earlier post on the real-world experiences / beginning inspiration behind this project (tldr; I was in Japan for three days and it was a lot of fun), I wanted to spend some time documenting how I went about putting together the visualization.
From the start, there was going to be some backend work and some frontend stuff. Because I wanted to build an app that could run purely client-side, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in Japan with Reflections and a Side Project</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006-tokyo_metro_markov_chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 23:18:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006-tokyo_metro_markov_chains/</guid>
      <description>Winter break&amp;rsquo;s been a long one. By now I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to being out of school, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to think that four weeks ago I was in Japan. Family&amp;rsquo;s been on a traveling kick lately, and this year we spent ten days between Tokyo, Kamakura, Hakone, Shanghai, and Beijing.
Although I&amp;rsquo;d been to Tokyo for some epsilon-long layovers before, and this time our time in Japan could probably still only be considered a layover (3 out of 10 days woo), I&amp;rsquo;d still consider the recent trip to be the first time I really got to see the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping out SummerCamp NYC 2018</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:29:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</guid>
      <description>Second part of a two-part series introducing SummerCamp NYC 2018. Also published on Medium here.
Part 2: Location, Location, &amp;hellip; Intern Preferences! If the students make up the heart of SummerCamp, the events bring them together and keep the community running. While ranging in size and nature, none of them would be possible without the fantastic hosts and partner companies we’ve been able to work with over the years, and a big part of organizing SummerCamp involves coordinating and planning for a series of meet-ups over the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>