<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Michael Zhang</title>
    <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Michael Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 23:57:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelzhang.xyz/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Tokyo Metro Markov Models</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006.1-tokyo_metro_markov-tech_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 23:57:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/006.1-tokyo_metro_markov-tech_post/</guid>
      <description>As a follow-up to an earlier post on the real-world experiences / beginning inspiration behind this project (tldr; I was in Japan for three days and it was a lot of fun), I wanted to spend some time documenting how I went about putting together the visualization.
From the start, there was going to be some backend work and some frontend stuff. Because I wanted to build an app that could run purely client-side, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping out SummerCamp NYC 2018</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:29:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-map-2018/</guid>
      <description>Second part of a two-part series introducing SummerCamp NYC 2018. Also published on Medium here.
Part 2: Location, Location, &amp;hellip; Intern Preferences! If the students make up the heart of SummerCamp, the events bring them together and keep the community running. While ranging in size and nature, none of them would be possible without the fantastic hosts and partner companies we’ve been able to work with over the years, and a big part of organizing SummerCamp involves coordinating and planning for a series of meet-ups over the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to SummerCamp NYC 2018</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-intro-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 22:43:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/004-summercamp_nyc-intro-2018/</guid>
      <description>Part of a two-part series introducing SummerCamp NYC 2018. Also published on Medium here.
Part 1: Meeting the Group of 2018 SummerCamp is a community of Harvard interns in the Bay Area, NYC, Seattle, and now Boston who come together every year to celebrate innovation and technology, focusing on the students and companies at the heart of it all. Through professional and social events, the group aims to connect students with each other, their alums, and leading technology-related companies in the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Engineering with CRISPR-Cas9 Virus-like Particles</title>
      <link>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/002-crispr_vlps-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 01:37:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelzhang.xyz/posts/002-crispr_vlps-post/</guid>
      <description>See the paper, poster, and research plan 
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if anyone will ever happen to be on this site looking for resources regarding science fairs, and I definitely don&amp;rsquo;t do as much wet-lab biology as I used to, but as an homage to a past high school obsession passion I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be nice to try to remember some past work.
Some Abstract For some introduction, CRISPR-Cas9 is an exciting gene editing technology with many hyped applications in science and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>